To find her son, she did what no one else dared.
Changeling is a crime, drama, mystery film directed by Clint Eastwood.
Los Angeles, 1928.
When single mother Christine Collins leaves for
work, her son vanishes without a trace.
Five months later, the police reunite mother and son.
But when Christine suspects that the boy returned to her isn't her
child, her quest for truth exposes a world of corruption.
Christine Collins, played by Angelina Jolie.
Rev. Gustav Briegleb, played by John Malkovich.
Captain J.J. Jones, played by Jeffrey Donovan.
Detective Lester Ybarra, played by Michael Kelly.
Chief James E. Davis, played by Colm Feore.
Gordon Northcott, played by Jason Butler Harner.
Changeling is a 2008 American mystery and crime drama film directed,
produced, and scored by Clint Eastwood and written by J.
Michael Straczynski.
The story was based on real-life events, specifically the 1928
Wineville Chicken Coop murders in Mira Loma, California.
It stars Angelina Jolie as a woman united with a boy
who she realizes is not her missing son.
When she tries to demonstrate that to the police and city authorities, she is vilified as
delusional, labeled as an unfit mother and confined to a psychiatric ward.
The film explores themes of child endangerment, female disempowerment,
political corruption, and mistreatment of mental health patients.
Working in 1983 as a special correspondent for the now defunct TV-Cable Week magazine, Straczynski first
learned the story of Christine Collins and her son from a Los Angeles City Hall contact.
Over the ensuing years he kept researching the story but
never felt he was ready to tackle it.
Out of television writing for several years and known to be difficult to work with, he
returned to researching and then finally writing the story in 2006.
Almost all of the film's script was drawn from
thousands of pages of documentation.
Ron Howard had intended to direct the film, but scheduling
conflicts led to his replacement by Eastwood.
Howard and his Imagine Entertainment partner Brian Grazer produced Changeling
alongside Malpaso Productions' Robert Lorenz and Eastwood.
Universal Pictures financed and distributed the film.
Several actors campaigned for the leading role; ultimately, Eastwood
decided that Jolie's face would suit the 1920s period setting.
The film also stars Jeffrey Donovan, Jason Butler Harner,
John Malkovich, Michael Kelly and Amy Ryan.
While some characters are composites, most are based on actual people.
Principal photography, which began on October 15, 2007, and concluded a few weeks later in
December, took place in Los Angeles and other locations in southern California.
Actors and crew noted that Eastwood's low-key direction
resulted in a calm set and short working days.
In post production, scenes were supplemented with
computer-generated skylines, backgrounds, vehicles and people.
Changeling premiered to critical acclaim at the 61st
Cannes Film Festival on May 20, 2008.
Additional festival screenings preceded a limited release in the United States on October 24, 2008, followed by a general release in
North America on October 31, 2008; in the United Kingdom on November 26, 2008; and in Australia on February 5, 2009.
Critical reaction was more mixed than at Cannes.
While the acting and story were generally praised, the film's
"conventional staging" and "lack of nuance" were criticized.
Changeling earned $113 million in box-office revenue worldwide—of which
$35.7 million came from the United States and Canada.
Changeling earned Jolie numerous award nominations including the Academy Award for Best Actress, the BAFTA Award for Best Actress in a Leading Role, the Critics' Choice Movie Award for Best
Actress, the Golden Globe Award for Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama and the Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Female Actor in a Leading Role.
The film explores themes of biography, based on true story,
clergyman, child in peril, police corruption.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.